<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Phaser.Sprite | One Broken Pixel]]></title>
  <link href="http://rieya-uc.github.io/blog/categories/phaser-dot-sprite/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rieya-uc.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-25T20:52:58+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://rieya-uc.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rieya]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drag the Square]]></title>
    <link href="http://rieya-uc.github.io/blog/2014/06/11/drag-the-square/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-11T16:01:37+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://rieya-uc.github.io/blog/2014/06/11/drag-the-square</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This one took somewhat longer than I expected. I wanted to create a collection of sprites that could be dragged around the screen as one.</p>

<p>Click the button to make a random rectangle appear somewhere on screen. Drag it around, then add a few more.</p>

<!--more-->


<script type="text/javascript">
    var path = '../../../../../blog_demos/';
</script>




<div id="demo" class="centre">

    <script type="text/javascript" src= "../../../../../blog_demos/libs/phaser.min.js"></script>
    <script type="text/javascript" src= "../../../../../blog_demos/drag_square/Square.js"></script>
    <script type="text/javascript" src= "../../../../../blog_demos/drag_square/drag_square.js"></script>
</div>


<pre><br></pre>


<p>The rectangle (Square.js), is made up of several sprites; its body and four borders. They are contained in an extended Phaser.Group (see <a href="http://examples.phaser.io/_site/view_full.html?d=groups&amp;f=extending+a+group.js&amp;t=extending%20a%20group">example</a>). Groups have no dimensions, which means no click area, and no drag event. Therefore to get the rectangle to move as one, I enabled drag on the body and kept the borders aligned during <code>update()</code>.</p>

<p>Everything inside a Group is moved relative to the Group&rsquo;s position. Don&rsquo;t do what I did and move the Group after the body&rsquo;s been dragged as an alternative to aligning the sprites individually, because you&rsquo;ll find the body has moved twice as far and your rectangle will be rectangular in name only. I found it simpler to keep all Groups at position (0,0), and position the sprites relative to that. The downside to doing it this way is that moving the Group via <code>(group.x, group.y) = some position</code> screws up the drag.</p>

<p>I think that if I were to redo this, I would forego drag altogether and use mousedown events instead, so that I could move the Group as a whole, and not the individual sprites.</p>

<p>Code? All available on <a href="https://github.com/rieya-uc/blog_demos">github</a>, and in the drag_square folder specifically.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
